<resources>
    <string name="app_name" formatted="false">Scriptarium</string>
    <string name="title_ideas">Idea</string>
    <string name="title_favorites">Poems</string>
    <string name="title_materials">Materials</string>
    <string name="literal_mov">Literal movements</string>
    <string name="genres">Genres</string>
    <string name="literary_flows">literary movements</string>
    <string name="literary_genres">Genres</string>
    <string name="ok">ОК</string>
    <string-array name="type_of_definitions">

        <item>Movements</item>
        <item>Genres</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="genres_names">
        <item>Epos</item>
        <item>Romance</item>
        <item>Story</item>
        <item>Opinion</item>
        <item>Novela</item>
        <item>Parable</item>
        <item>Legend</item>
        <item>Myth</item>
        <item>Tale</item>
        <item>Lyric</item>
        <item>Song</item>
        <item>Verse</item>
        <item>Ode to</item>
        <item>Anthem</item>
        <item>Elegy</item>
        <item>Drama</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="Epos">Epos</string>
    <string name="Romance">Romance</string>
    <string name="story">Story</string>
    <string name="Opinion">Opinion</string>
    <string name="Novela">Novela</string>
    <string name="Parable">Parable</string>
    <string name="Legend">Legend</string>
    <string name="Myth">Myth</string>
    <string name="Tale">Tale</string>
    <string name="Lyric">Lyric</string>
    <string name="Song">Song</string>
    <string name="Verse">Verse</string>
    <string name="Ode_to">Ode to</string>
    <string name="Anthem">Anthem</string>
    <string name="Elegy">Elegy</string>
    <string name="Drama">Drama</string>


    <string name="epos_describe">(ἔπος - a "word", a "story") is a variety of literary family(equally with a lyric poetry and drama), that tells about
        events that allegedly took place in the past(as if came true in actual fact and remembered by retell).
    </string>
    <string name="Romance_describe">large on a volume and difficult after a structure epic work important and difficult public processes are widely
        overcame in that, all-round and numerous personages are shown in development.
    </string>
    <string name="story_describe">epic prosaic work(rarer written in verse) that is characterized an unilinear plot, and after the breadth of scope of
        the vital phenomena and in depth their opening an intermediate place will take a seat between a novel and story.
    </string>
    <string name="Opinion_describe">small prosaic work a plot of that is base on certain(rarely a few) episode from one(sometimes a few) life to the
        personage.
    </string>
    <string name="Novela_describe">small prosaic work a plot of that is base on certain(rarely a few) episode from one(sometimes a few) life to the
        personage.
    </string>
    <string name="Parable_describe">short folklore or literary narrative work of instructive character, oriented mainly to the allegoric form of leading
        to of maintenance of ethic values of existence
    </string>
    <string name="Legend_describe">folk conversation or recital is of some events or life of people, obvolute fabulousness, fantasy
    </string>
    <string name="Myth_describe">ancient folk story about the phenomena of nature, historical events and others like that or fantastic recitals of Gods,
        adorable heroes, imaginary creatures.</string>
    <string name="Tale_describe">folklore narrative work about invented, and often and fantastic events..</string>
    <string name="Lyric_describe">(грец. lyrikós - lyre; work executed under accompaniment of lyre) - one of three luing-ins of fiction and art in that
        in form естетизованих experiencing essence of human existence is comprehended; does not have a sharp-edged plot‚ for her characteristic verse
        form‚ plenty of artistic facilities‚ high level of emotionality.
</string>
    <string name="Song_describe"> verse of lyric or lyrico-epic character, melodious after the intonation picture and intended for singing.</string>
    <string name="Verse_describe">small poetic work written with a ритмізованою language, mostly with rhyming of lines</string>
    <string name="Ode_to_describe">verse, that expresses the elevated feelings, caused by important historical events, activity of historical persons.</string>
    <string name="Anthem_describe">solemn song accepted as a state or social symbol; a piece of music of solemn character is in the, symphonic, choral
        opera.</string>
    <string name="Elegy_describe">it is work of meditation character, sad key, poetic with a plot basis of that is an emotional reaction on certain
        events, situation, psychical impulses(it is heard, mentioned, пережите) or certain emotional state of lyric "Я", that is overcame by a
        melancholy, sorrow, even suffering.
</string>
    <string name="Drama_describe">(дав.-гр. δρᾶμα it is a "action", "act", "action") - one of literary luing-ins, that represents the world in form
        action, mostly intended for a stage embodiment.</string>




    <string-array name="genres_description">
        <item>(ἔπος - a "word", a "story") is a variety of literary family(equally with a lyric poetry and drama), that tells about events that allegedly took place in the past(as if came true in actual fact and remembered by retell).</item>
        <item>large on a volume and difficult after a structure epic work important and difficult public processes are widely
        overcame in that, all-round and numerous personages are shown in development.</item>
        <item>epic prosaic work(rarer written in verse) that is characterized an unilinear plot, and after the breadth of scope of
        the vital phenomena and in depth their opening an intermediate place will take a seat between a novel and story.</item>
        <item>small prosaic work a plot of that is base on certain(rarely a few) episode from one(sometimes a few) life to the
        personage.</item>
        <item>small prosaic work a plot of that is base on certain(rarely a few) episode from one(sometimes a few) life to the
        personage.</item>
        <item>short folklore or literary narrative work of instructive character, oriented mainly to the allegoric form of leading
        to of maintenance of ethic values of existence</item>
        <item>folk conversation or recital is of some events or life of people, obvolute fabulousness, fantasy</item>
        <item>ancient folk story about the phenomena of nature, historical events and others like that or fantastic recitals of Gods,
        adorable heroes, imaginary creatures</item>
        <item>folklore narrative work about invented, and often and fantastic events..</item>
        <item>(грец. lyrikós - lyre; work executed under accompaniment of lyre) - one of three luing-ins of fiction and art in that
        in form естетизованих experiencing essence of human existence is comprehended; does not have a sharp-edged plot‚ for her characteristic verse
        form‚ plenty of artistic facilities‚ high level of emotionality.</item>
        <item>verse of lyric or lyrico-epic character, melodious after the intonation picture and intended for singing.</item>
        <item>small poetic work written with a ритмізованою language, mostly with rhyming of lines</item>
        <item>verse, that expresses the elevated feelings, caused by important historical events, activity of historical persons.</item>
        <item>solemn song accepted as a state or social symbol; a piece of music of solemn character is in the, symphonic, choral
        opera.</item>
        <item>it is work of meditation character, sad key, poetic with a plot basis of that is an emotional reaction on certain
        events, situation, psychical impulses(it is heard, mentioned, пережите) or certain emotional state of lyric "Я", that is overcame by a
        melancholy, sorrow, even suffering.</item>
        <item>(дав.-гр. δρᾶμα it is a "action", "act", "action") - one of literary luing-ins, that represents the world in form
        action, mostly intended for a stage embodiment.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="literary_movement">
        <item>Baroque</item>
        <item>Classicism</item>
        <item>Sentimentalism</item>
        <item>Romanticism</item>
        <item>Realism</item>
        <item>Modernism</item>
        <item>Decadence</item>
        <item>Neo-romanticism</item>
        <item>Impressionism</item>
        <item>Expressionism</item>
        <item>Symbolism</item>
        <item>Neoclassicism</item>
        <item>Futurism</item>
        <item>Neorealism</item>
        <item>Existentialism</item>
        <item>Postmodernism</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="movements_description">
    <item>a trend in European literature of the early XVI century — late XVIII century,
        characterized by a combination of religious and secular motifs, images, attraction to
        different, contrasts, complex metaphors, allegory and emblematic, the desire to impress the
        reader with lush, colorful style, rhetorical decoration.
</item>
        <item>a trend in European literature, in the XVII century — early XIX century, which is
            characterized by a focus on ancient literature, which was proclaimed ideal, classical,
            worthy of imitation.</item>
        <item>a trend in European literature of the second half of the 18th and the beginning of the
            19th centuries, which is characterized by the desire to recreate the world of ordinary
            people's feelings and evoke the reader's sympathy for the heroes of the work.</item>
        <item>a trend in European literature and art of the late XVIII — early XIX centuries.,
            Whose representatives fought against the canons of classicism, brought to the fore the
            interests of the individual and feelings and used in their work historical and folk poetry.
</item>
        <item>a literary trend that is characterized by a true and comprehensive reflection of
            reality based on the typification of life phenomena.
</item>
        <item>a total term denoting a set of literary trends and schools of the XX century, which
            are characterized by creativity, experimentation, attraction to conventional means,
            anti-realist orientation.</item>
        <item>a literary trend marked by feelings of hopelessness, frustration, loss of vitality,
            and aestheticism.</item>
        <item>the conditional name of aesthetic tendencies that emerged in world culture,
            in particular in literature, painting and music, which is traditionally
            associated with modernist reactions to positivism and naturalism in the
            late XIX — early XX centuries.
</item>
        <item> an artistic direction based on the principle of direct fixation of impressions,
            observations, empathy.

</item>
        <item>a literary and artistic stylistic trend of avant-garde that emerged in
            Germany in the early twentieth century.</item>
        <item>a literary trend of the late XIX - early XX centuries, the main feature of
            which is that a particular artistic image becomes a multifaceted symbol.
</item>
        <item>a trend in literature, which found expression in the use of ancient themes and plots,
            mythological images and motifs, the proclamation of the slogans of "pure" art and worship
            devoid of social meaning art form, in glorifying earthly pleasures that emerged
            in Western European literature in the mid-nineteenth century.
</item>
        <item>a literary trend that emerged in the early twentieth century in Italy,
            which is characterized by images of large industrial cities, their atmosphere and
            way of life; the cult of the superman who rules the world through scientific advances.
</item>
        <item>  a stylistic trend in Ukrainian literature and world literature of
            the early twentieth century, which is also called socio-psychological, romantic,
            impressionistic or lyrical-psychological realism, which developed from classical realism.
</item>
        <item> a trend in twentieth-century philosophy that positions and explores
            man as a unique spiritual being capable of choosing his own destiny.
</item>
        <item>a literary movement that emerged in the United States and Europe in the late
            twentieth century, the aesthetic nature of which is associated with pluralism -
            the concept of having many different views, positions, ideas and interests
            at the same time.</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>